playpennies.com 2018-12-27

# Privacy Policy - Playpennies

## PLAYPENNIES PRIVACY STATEMENT

This Privacy Statement covers the types of personal information we collect, how we use it and the steps we take to protect it. We collect information through website cookies and your input on our website when you post comments, vote, take part in competitions, register for notifications or contact us directly.

### The types of data we collect 

Activity 

| 

Type of Data 

| 

Basis   
  
---|---|---  
  
When you register or make a comment on our website 

| 

Contact 

Profile 

Technical 

| 

Mutually beneficial relationship 

Our legitimate interest (updating records and understanding how our users use our services)   
  
We maintain our relationship (to include feedback requests and changes to our policies) 

| 

Contact 

Profile 

Usage 

| 

Mutually beneficial relationship 

Legal compliance 

Our legitimate interest (updating records and understanding how our users use our services)   
  
If you agree to receiving correspondence from us (to include sending updates and news from our websites, including relevant content but also administrative updates such as site maintenance and reporting) 

| 

Contact 

Technical 

Profile 

Usage 

Communications and Marketing 

| 

Our legitimate interest (updating records and understanding how users use our services) 

Our legitimate interests (for running our business) 

Legal compliance   
  
If you join our email marketing list to participate in promotions and competitions 

| 

Contact 

Profile 

Communications and Marketing 

| 

Our legitimate interest (updating records and understanding how users use our services)   
  
When you use our site 

| 

Technical 

Usage 

| 

Our legitimate interest (updating records and understanding how users use our services)   
  
### If you comment on our website 

If you decide to register on our site and make comments on any of our articles, the username and email address you enter and your comment will be saved to our database, along with your computer’s IP address and the timestamp of the comment. This profile information is only used to identify you as a contributor within the article’s comment section and is not passed on to any third party data processors. 

You should avoid publishing or posting any personally identifiable information. Upfeat is not responsible for content that you post on our website and we ask you do not post content that could violate the privacy of others. 

Your comment and any data associated with it will remain on this site until we either remove the comment or remove the blog post. If you wish to have the comment and it’s associated personal data deleted, please email us here using the email address that you commented with. 

### If you email us 

When you contact us through the website or fill out our online form, we collect contact data from you, such as your name and email address. This information is only used to fulfil the service you have requested or to contact you in regards to your inquiries.

### If you opt in to our newsletter  

If you choose to join our email newsletter and provide your contact data to us, we’ll use it to send you updates, communications and marketing from our website as well as any promotions or competitions we might run for our subscribers in future. 

Your contact data will be forwarded to our email marketing provider, a compliant third party data processor. Your email address will remain within the marketing provider’s database for as long as we continue to use their services for email marketing or until you specifically request removal from the list. You can do this by unsubscribing using the unsubscribe links contained in any email newsletters that we send you or by requesting removal via email at any time. 

### When you use our site 

When you visit our website, we use cookies to collect technical and usage data, such as your IP address or unique device id. We use this information to understand how you use our site features, and your browsing habits. This helps us to evolve our website with you in mind, ensuring we make smart decisions and you can have the best browsing experience. Cookie usage also helps us to prevent malicious behaviour and abuse of services, protecting our site and the people who use it. 

We and our providers also make use of cookies to help promote our services through marketing and advertising. At no time do we pass any cookie personal data to a third party for their own purposes. 

You can opt-out of cookies or prevent third party websites from accessing our cookies through the privacy settings on your browser. That will disable, however, some features of our website. 

### How we protect your information 

We store the personal information we collect on secure servers directly controlled by us and are fully committed to ensuring your data is secure at all times. From time to time we may use third party cloud technology partners to help us store and process some of this data. In those cases, we enter into data protection agreements with these third party providers, to ensure that they use similar levels of protection and they adhere to our privacy policy. We also make sure that your personal information is transmitted in accordance with these agreements and as securely as possible using industry standard practices. 

### Where your information is stored 

You data is stored in a secure cloud - cloud data can be stored within multiple locations by our cloud service providers, from time to time your information may be transferred to and stored in secure locations outside the EEA 

Regular audits and appropriate safeguards are in place for all transfers both within and outside of the EEA 

### How we share information 

We never disclose your personal data unless it is with your consent or as authorised or required by law. We may share your personal information collected with third party service providers to help us provide our services to you, such as sending you notification emails, and only if such information is required to provide you with the specific services. When we do this, we enter into data protection agreements with these service providers and ensure that they all comply with our privacy policy. In cases when we are providing these webpages on behalf of another party, we may share personal & usage data only with the party we are providing the service for and according to its instructions. 

### Your rights and how you can access or modify your personal information 

You have the right to: 

  * Request access to your data (ask us what information we store related to you)
  * Request correction to your data
  * Request erasure
  * Request transfer of your data
  * Withdraw consent at any time

You can submit a request to access, edit or remove the personal information you have provided to us by contacting privacy+playpennies@upfeat.com. If you find your information is inaccurate, we will correct or delete it, as needed. You can withdraw your consent to us holding the information you provided at any time. 

Our website is not aimed at children and we do not knowingly collect the data of minors. 

We will process your request within 15 business days. 

### Contact us 

For privacy and personal information queries and concerns, please contact: Upfeat Media Inc, 200-171 McDermot Ave, Winnipeg MB, R3G0X7, Canada, or by email at: privacy+playpennies@upfeat.com. Should your concerns remain unaddressed, you can contact the Data Protection Authority in your country or the Office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada.
